嗨大家，歡迎來到介紹性 Python 教學，特別關注於影像處理
hi everyone welcome to introductory python tutorials with a special focus on image processing
在這段影片中，我們來看看如何使用編碼器建構單位
in this video let's have a look at building a unit using encoder
和解碼塊
and decoder blocks
那意味著什麼？在教程 115 中，那個
what does that mean well in tutorial 115 the one
在這之前，不是這個之前的那個，而是再之前的那個，上一個
before not the one before this but the one before that one the previous one
我們查看了單位
we looked at unit
然後我們實際上通過定義每一層來建立單位，就像我們定義了兩個卷積層一樣
and we actually built unit by defining every layer like we defined two convolution layers
然後是激活層對吧
and then activation right
然後我們定義了卷積層，抱歉，還有最大池化，兩個卷積層和最大池化
and then we defined convolution layer sorry and max pooling two convolution layers max pooling
以此類推
and so on
我們意識到有一些模式這些區塊在重複
and we realized that there are some patterns these blocks are repeating
那麼如何將這些定義為單獨的函數呢
so how about defining those as separate functions
編碼器
for encoder
和解碼器
and decoder
然後實際上用幾行代碼構建一個單元
and then actually with a few lines of code build a unit
這樣做可能非常有用
and this can be very useful
如果你真的希望定義一個幾乎像是通用的單位
if you really would like to define a almost like a universal unit
只需更改幾個參數
where you just change a couple of parameters
然後您可以將此功能自訂為二元分割
and then you can customize this for binary segmentation
您可以將此功能自訂為多類別分割
you can customize this for multi-class segmentation
那麼擴展到 3D 主題怎麼樣
how about extending this to 3d topic
對，所以你可以，你可以
right so you can you can
你可以自己建造單位
you can build your own units
這不是非常困難
this is not very difficult
那我們就來看看怎麼做到這點
so let's go ahead and see how we can do that
再次快速回顧這個單元，這是原始文獻中的單元
and again a quick recap of unit this is the unit from original paper
和
and
如您所見，我們正在往下進行
as you can see we are going down
隨著我們往下進行，會有一些特定的操作
and there are certain specific operations as we go down
以及在視頻 115 教學 115 中
and in the video 115 tutorial 115
我們檢視了使用 256 x 256 來實現這個單元
we looked at implementing this unit using 256 by 256
1 圖像，這裡是我們檢視的結構
1 images here is the structure that we looked at
我們說好，從 256 減少到 128
and we said okay going from 256 to 128
減少到 64，然後到 32，再到 16。再次觀看最後的影片以了解這個解碼器部分
to 64 to 32 to 16 right again watch the last video to understand this decoder part
我們討論了上採樣
we talked about up sampling
我們也談到了 2D 轉置
we also talked about con 2d transpose either way
從 16 x 16 到 32，再到 64，再到 128
you're going from 16 by 16 to 32 to 64 to 128
最終到 256
and finally to 256
這恰好是我們圖像的原始大小
which happens to be the original size of our image
因為您希望分割後的圖像與原始圖像大小相同
because you want your segmented image to be the same size as your original image
好的
yeah
所以
so
我們是通過在這裡編寫每一行來構建這個的
we built this by writing each line here
所以這是我的輸入
so this is my input
然後接著是兩個卷積層
and then comes two convolutional layers
以及最大池化，兩個卷積，最大池化，右側，這正是
and max pooling two convolution max pooling right this is exactly
我們有兩個卷積
what we have two convolutions
藍色箭頭最大池化，紅色箭頭兩個卷積，藍色箭頭，紅色箭頭
the blue arrows max pulling red arrow two convolution blue arrows red arrow
然後我們意識到有一堆這些內容在重複
and so on then we realized a bunch of these are repeating
那為什麼不直接分配區塊呢
so why not just assign blocks
所以
so
那我們這麼說的意思是什麼，例如
what do we mean by that for example
讓我們來看看這兩個操作
let's look at these two operations right there
所以我們正在進行卷積，我們正在進行卷積
so we are performing a convolution right we are performing a convolution convolution
和最大池化
and max pooling
輸出是什麼
what is the output
在每個這些之後
after each of these
所以我正在分配某些
so i'm assigning certain
我說，卷積層的輸出是 s1
certain name to it i'm saying okay the output of my convolution layers is s1
在這一點上，我的卷積層的輸出是 s1
the output of my convolution layers is s1 at this point
最大池化的輸出是 p1
and the output of max pooling is p1
好的，讓我們回到這個第二次操作的輸出是 s1
okay let's go back the output of this second operation is s1
池化的輸出是 p1
and the output of the pooling is p1
一切將會在一秒鐘內完成
everything will come together in a second
所以
so
在第一層，convert2d 的輸出是 256
at the first layer the output of convert2d is 256
因為我們沒有進行任何池化，什麼都沒有，只是會有 64 個濾波器
because we are not doing any pooling nothing it's just that we'll have 64 filters
到目前為止，這個的大小是 256。
at this point the size of this is 256.
我們有 64 個過濾器
we have 64 filters
在最大池化後，大小縮小到 128。
after max pooling the size goes down to 128.
現在回到代碼
now go back to the code
所以在這一點上
so at this point
s1 的大小為 256
s1 has a size of 256
p1 的大小為 128
p1 has a size of 128.
這裡的 s2 大小為 128
here s2 has a size of 128
因為
because
s2 是什麼？它來自 p1 的輸入
what is s2 it's coming the input from p1
是的，我們再來看一下這個圖示
yeah again let's look at this in the diagram here
所以這是輸入，這是 p1，這個輸入進入了我的 s2
so this is the input this is the p1 that input is going into my s2
好，就在那裡
okay right there
然後
and then
在 s2 操作之後，你會得到下一步
after the s2 operation you get the next step
以此類推
and so on
那麼我們來指定某些參數
so let's assign certain certain parameters
變數
variables
因此，這讓我們容易定義我們的模型
so it makes it easy for us to define our model
所以假設卷積輸出是 s1
so let's say the convolution output is s1
而最大池化輸出是那裡的 p1
and the max pooling output is p1 right there
在這一點，這個箭頭的尖端，這兩件事
at this point at the tip of this arrow the two things
我們需要的其中之一是 s1
that we need one is s1
另一個是 p1，s1 對應於這個卷積層的輸出
the other one is p1 s1 corresponds to the output of this convolution layer
和 p1 對應於這個最大池化的輸出
and p1 corresponds to the output of this max pooling that goes
作為下一個的輸入，為什麼我們需要卷積的輸出
as input to the next one why do we need the output of convolution
在最大池化之前，當我們說這個時候，我在說輸出
before max pooling right when we say that i'm saying output
在最大池化之前，為什麼我需要那個？我需要那個
before max pooling why do i need that well i need that
這樣我才能將該輸出發送到這一層進行串接
so i can send that output to this layer right here for concatenation
這就是單元的作用
that's what unit is
那麼如果我們回來，我拿我的 S1
so if we come back if i take my s1
那個 S1 連接到 D4 就在那裡，這就是原因
that s1 is connected to d4 right there this is the reason
我希望我的 S1 作為單獨的輸出
i want my s1 as a separate output
我希望到目前為止一切順利
i hope so far so good
那麼我們現在繼續這個，所以 s1 p1 s2 p2 s3 p3
so let's now continue this so s1 p1 s2 p2 s3 p3
每完成這些後，你會得到
after each of these you get
卷積輸出最大拉伸輸出
the convolution output max pulling output
而且你就有了基底
and you have the base right there
好的，就在這裡
okay right here
在這之後，我們會向上移動，同時我們會有我們的解碼器，一個解碼器
after this we are going up while going up we have our our decoder one decoder
我們不需要發送
two we don't need to send
當我們上升時會有兩個輸出，因為我們沒有做任何事
two outputs while we are going up because we are not doing
我們所需要的只是來自這裡的輸出
anything with that all we need is output from here
這可以作為輸入提供給下一個解碼器區塊
that can be provided as input to the next decoder block
所以每個解碼區塊編碼區塊我們稍後會定義
so each of this decoder block encoder block we'll define that in a second
所以輸出是 d1 d2 d3
so the outputs are d1 d2 d3
然後 d4 基本上是朝向你的輸出
and then d4 is basically going towards your output
現在讓我們定義一下，識別一些重複的
so now let's define let's identify some repetitive
模式。這裡你可以看到藍色的框，這些是重複的
patterns here you see the blue boxes here these are repetitive
卷積塊
convolutional blocks
如果你只看這兩個藍色箭頭，就是這樣
if you just look at this two blue arrows that's it
兩個藍色箭頭 兩個藍色箭頭 兩個藍色箭頭
two blue arrows two blue arrows two blue arrows
即使是回到上面，你也有卷積層對吧
and so on even going back up you have the convolution layers right
為什麼不將其定義為一個函數
so why not define that as a function
這是第一步，我們會這麼做
that's step number one we'll do that
那我們要怎麼做呢
and how do we do that
所以在我們的情況下，卷積區塊我們要定義的方式是 convert2d
so in our case the convolution block the way we are going to define is convert2d
對，那是 conf2d
right that's conf2d
然後你可以定義下一個 2D 轉換
and then you can define the next conver 2d
但我正在添加批量正則化
but i am adding batch normalization
所以這有點平衡了事物，批量正則化非常好
so it it kind of balances things out bash normalization is very good
你知道，它使得融合變得稍微容易一些
you know it it makes convergence
讓我這麼說吧，再次觀看批次正規化的影片
a bit easier let me put it that way again watch the video on batch normalization
但只是快速提醒一下
but just a quick note
所以這個矩形上面寫著 64，就是這部分代碼
so this rectangle that says 64 up here is this part of the code
基本上是 convert2d 加上批量正規化
which is basically convert2d with batch normalization
然後應用 Rayleigh 激活函數，就是這樣
and then applying rayleigh activation right so here
將濾波器大小設為三乘三
con to a three by three is my filter size right there
然後是射頻激活
and then radioactivation
我做的就是添加偏差正規化，就這樣
all i did is add bias normalization that's it
然後第二個就在那裡
and then the second one right there
這與第一個相當相似，對立批次啟用
which is pretty much the same as the first one contrary batch activation
這是我的卷積區塊
this is my convolution block
好的
okay
還有什麼在重複
what else is repeating
這個區塊正在重複
this block is repeating
卷積區塊加上最大池化
convolution block plus max pooling
我的意思是你可能會認為
i mean you may think
這些是相同的，藍色框直到那一點沒有最大池化
these are the same the blue box is up to that point without max pooling
紅色框是使用最大池化
the red box is with max pooling
這在編碼器中也重複出現
this is also repeating in the encoder
四乘一二三四
four times one two three four
那麼我們來定義編碼器區塊
so let's define the encoder block
這什麼都不是
which is nothing
但這是卷積區塊的組合
but a combination of convolution block
和最大
and max
池化
pooling
這個編碼器區塊給我們兩個輸出 s1
and this encoder block is giving us two outputs s1
或 s
or s
而 p 正確，這裡我叫它 x
and p right again here i called it x
但把這個視為 s
but think of this as s
好的
okay
這是來自卷積區塊的輸出，即你的 x
which is the output from convolution block is your x
而 p 是來自最大池化的輸出
and p is the output from the max pooling
所以這是這兩個
so these are the two
你知道我們為什麼需要 x，我們需要 x
and you know exactly why we need x we need x
這樣我們就可以與任何那個進行連接
so we can concatenate with whatever that
d 在那邊
d is over there
我們需要 p
we need p
這樣可以進入下一個卷積塊
so that can go into the next convolution block
或者編碼器塊，如果你想這麼稱呼的話
or encoder block if you want to call it
好的
okay
還有什麼在重複
what else is repeating
這些綠色的方塊，對，就是這些，它們是解碼塊。我們之前有編碼塊在下方。
these green boxes right these are decoded blocks previously we had encoder blocks going down
現在我們有了解碼塊。編碼塊和解碼塊之間有什麼區別？
now we have decoder block what's the difference between encoder
和解碼塊，它們有點對稱。
and decoder block they're kind of symmetric
但在這裡我們有連接
but here we have concatenation
所以我們需要添加它
so we need to add that
所以讓我們繼續添加它，我的解碼器區塊接收輸入
so let's go ahead and add it my decoder block takes in input
從前一層
from the previous layer
跳過功能是快捷方式
skip features are the shortcuts
他們稱之為
they call the
我是說，這是用來跳過功能的快捷鍵的常見術語
i mean it's common terminology for the shortcuts are skip features
所以這就是那個意思
so that's what that is
和過濾器的數量
and number of filters
那麼首先會發生什麼操作
so what operation happens first
你可以看到這裡兩兩對話，所以我們將進行 2D 轉置
you see up here up convo two by two so we are going to perform con 2d transpose
或者你可以進行上採樣，然後再進行卷積
or you can do up sampling you know followed by convolution
但這只是遵循這種矛盾轉置
but this this just follow this contradi transpose
並且需要多個濾波器
and it takes number of filters
所以如果我說我的濾波器數量是 256
so if my if i say my number of filters is 256
這就是我如果過濾器數量為 128 時得到的結果
that's what i get if my number of filters is 128 that's what i get
在這個綠色列之後的 2D 操作到這個輸出
after this green column 2d operation to this output
我需要添加從那裡來的輸入
i need to add the input coming from there
所以這正是
so that's exactly
跳過計數功能的用途
what the skip count features are for
所以連接
so concatenate
這個輸出
this output
和跳過功能一起，這就是那個區塊
and the skip features together this is that block right there
一旦你連接
and once you concatenate
添加卷積區塊，記住這部分是 Karma 區塊
add the convolution block remember this part is the karma block
對，我們重複這樣做只是為了說明這部分，藍色框是卷積
right we're repeating it just to say this part the blue box is the conve
所以在串接之後
so after concatenating
就是做那個卷積區塊，正是如此
just do the convolution block that's exactly
我們嘗試在那裡做的卷積區塊
what we are trying to do there convolution block
那並不簡單
isn't that simple
好的
okay
所以這就是在這裡
so this is where
現在你可以稍微看到
now you can kind of see
這如何適合
how this fits in
好的
yeah
所以這些輸出
so these outputs
和
and
現在讓我們把這些整合在一起以建構這個單元
now let's put all of this together to build this unit
你如何將它們組合在一起？這樣就可以了
how do you put them together there you go
所以
so
在輸入上應用一個具有 64 個濾波器的編碼器區塊，這就是你所得到的
apply an encoder block on the input with 64 filters there you go that's where you get
編碼器區塊能給你什麼
and what does an encoder block give you
編碼器區塊給你的輸出是什麼，它給你
what output does an encoder block give you it gives you
跳過連接就像是卷積區塊的輸出
the skip connection like the output of the convolution block
和最大池化
and max pooling
再次重申這一點，因為這很重要
again i'm repeating this because this is important
第一個，這個 x 是連接的
the first one this one x is concatenated
p 進入下一級
p goes to the next level
好的
okay
那我們回到之前的
so let's go back
它給你兩樣東西，對吧
it gives you two things right x
現在我稱它為 s1
now i'm calling it s1
和 p1
and p1
p1 是進入下一個編碼器區塊的部分，這是下一個具有 128 的編碼器區塊
p1 is what goes to the next encoder block right this is the next encoder block with 128
過濾器，就是 p1 的位置，這個編碼器區塊給你 s2
filters that's where p1 is this encoder block gives you s2
以及 p2 作為輸出
and p2 as outputs
然後它一直延續到這個基礎 b1
and then it continues all the way down to this base b1
然後在這裡的解碼器區塊，我們正在處理 b1
and then the decoder block here we are taking b1
就在那裡
right there
然後我們將那部分複製到這裡或將那部分連接到這裡
and then we copy that part here or we concatenate that part here
這是 s4 對吧
which is s4 right
是的，就在那裡，抱歉，s4
yeah right there sorry s4
這個是 s4，我把它放在這裡，可能有點混淆
this one is s4 i put it down here can be a bit confusing
但 s4 是來自這裡的卷積輸出
but s4 is the convolutional output coming from here
所以你把 s4 和 d1 放在一起
so you put s4 along with d1
然後你放入 s3
and then you put s3
就是從這裡出來的這個，還有 d2 對吧
which comes out of here this one along with d2 right
d d1 s3 對不起 d1 就在那裡 s3
d d1 s3 sorry d1 right there s3
然後來到 d2 s2
and then comes d2 s2
以此類推
and so on
所以你把這些東西串聯在一起
so you concatenate these things together
如果我錯了
if i got it wrong
繼續修正
go ahead and fix
它，但我們將在下一部分檢查它
it but we are going to check it out in our next
你知道，在本教程的下一部分
you know in the next part of this tutorial
我們無論如何都會查看代碼
where we look at the code anyway
所以如果有任何不匹配的地方，請不要擔心
so don't worry about any any of these here if there is a mismatch
但我不認為會有任何
but i don't think there is any
只是先跟你打個預防針
but just just giving you a heads up
所以最終
so finally
我的輸出是什麼？我的輸出是一個卷積
what is my output my output is a convolution
2D 操作，這是到目前為止的輸出，我們完成了
2d operation this is the output up to this point we are done
這最終的輸出是一個 2D 操作，使用逐一核
this final output is a con 2d operation with one by one kernel
和激活函數 sigmoid，對吧？這在這個例子中是一個二元的
and activation sigmoid right this is in this example this is a binary
語義分割
semantic segmentation
所以輸出
so the output
所以我將始終使用激活函數 sigmoid，請記住多類別分類
so i'm going to use activation sigmoid always remember multi-class classification
軟最大激活
soft max activation
二元分類
binary classification
sigmoid 激活
sigmoid activation
但這是語意分割
but this is semantic segmentation
我在說什麼，語意分割與分類是相同的
what am i talking about semantic segmentation is same as classification
除非你在對每個像素進行分類，而不是整個圖像
except you're classifying every pixel instead of the entire image
所以適用相同的規則
so the same rules apply
好的
okay
所以那就是你所在的位置
so that's where that's where you are
所以讓我們跳到代碼部分
so let's jump to the code
並查看我們是否能學到更多
and see if we can learn even more
好的
okay
所以完全相同的事情
so exactly the same thing
現在我正在匯入庫，讓我們繼續連接
now i'm importing the libraries let's go ahead and connect
首先
first of all
讓我們檢查執行時間
and let's check the runtime
更改運行時類型，我不使用 GPU
change runtime type i'm not using gpu
因為在這裡我們不需要 GPU，我們只是建立一個模型
because you don't need gpu here we are just building a model
好的，我們不會使用 GPU
okay we are not going to use gpu
好的
okay
從 keras.layers 匯入 input、Convolution2D、MaxPooling2D
so from keras dot layers i'm going to import the input con 2d max pooling 2d
如果你想使用上採樣
if you want to use up sampling
你可以使用它，但我將使用 Conv2DTranspose
go ahead and use it but i'm going to use contoury transpose
正如我之前展示的
as i already showed you
然後你可以添加中斷
and then you can add dropouts
及其他
and others
如果你想
if you want
那麼我們再次進行函式庫的匯入吧，這對你來說應該不會是新鮮事
so let's go ahead and import our libraries again this should be nothing new to you
現在讓我們來定義卷積
and now let's define the convolution
區塊，我不想重複我談過的所有內容，這實際上是
block again i don't want to repeat everything that i talked about this is literally
我們之前看到的，卷積區塊
what we saw earlier the convolution block
演示中的 OK
okay in the presentation
現在編碼器區塊什麼都沒有
now encoder block is nothing
只有具有最大池化的卷積區塊
but convolution block with max pooling
然後我們會給出卷積區塊的輸出
and then we give both the output of a convolution block
和最大池化，我們將返回這兩個
and the max pooling we we are going to return those two
而這些中的一個將作為下一步的輸入
and one of these like that one is going in as input for the next
解碼器區塊
decoder block
所以我們來定義解碼器
so let's go ahead and define the decoder
這就是我們構建單元的方式
and this is the way we build our unit
我早些時候在這段視頻錄製中添加了這個功能
and i added this function earlier to this recording of this video
哪裡
where
我說好，如果我的類別數量
i said okay if my number of classes
因為這是其中的一個輸入，如果我的類別數量等於 1
because that's one of the inputs right if my number of classes equal to 1
這意味著它是一個二元分類，記住二元分類意味著你只有一個類別
which means it's a binary classification remember binary classification means you have one class
和
and
問題被定義為背景為零
and the problem is defined as it's either background like zero
或者一
or one
這是二進位的
that's binary
所以你有一個黑暗的背景
so you have a dark background
而你的物體是明亮的
and you have like your objects in bright
所以這是二元分類
so this is binary classification
所以這是零或一，所以如果是這種情況，使用 sigmoid
so it's either zero or one so if that's the case use sigmoid
否則使用激活函數如 soft max
otherwise use activation as soft max
所以我們可以在任何情況下調用這個
so we can call this no matter
無論你知道多少
how many you know no matter
你要分割的類別數量
how many classes you're going to segment
好的
okay
那麼我們就開始吧
so let's go ahead and do that
那麼讓我們建立我們的單元，假設我的輸入形狀不僅僅是灰階
and let's build our unit let's say my input shape is not just a grayscale
而是一張顏色圖片 256x256x3
but a color image 256 by 256x3
而且我的類別數量等於 1。繼續並打印摘要
and my number of classes equals to 1. go ahead and print the summary
所以這是摘要，讓我們往下滾動
so here is the summary let's scroll down
然後從最上面開始
and start from the top
來了，它以 256 256 3 作為你的輸入層開始
there you go it starts with 256 256 3 as your input layer
然後 64 64 右邊
and then 64 64 right
一直往下到 1024
and so on all the way down to 1024
然後一直回到
and then all the way back to
這是二元的，再次是二元分類
256 256 1 y1 this is a binary again binary classification
所以你要麼有 0
so you either have 0
或 1。
or 1.
現在我們將這個改為多類別
now let's change this to a multi-class
我們如何將這個改為多類別
how do we change this to multi-class
所以對於多類別
so for multi-class
儘管我的輸入影像仍然是彩色的，您可以將其更改為灰階
still my input images are color here you can change that to grayscale
如果是灰階，您的輸入將是 256 到 56 1 對吧
if that is grayscale your input would be 256 to 56 1 right
但讓我們將其更改為彩色
but let's change that to color that
和類別數量，假設我有四個類別
and number of classes let's say i have four classes
四個不同的區域，我想在語義分割中識別，輸入四
four different regions that i want to identify in my semantic segmentation just type four
你會看到輸出層，它必須顯示四個
you see the output layer it has to come up with four
好的
yeah
那我們就往下走
so let's go down
然後你就這樣完成了 256 到 56 4。
and there you go 256 to 56 4.
好的
okay
然後一旦你有了模型，你只需要編譯
and then once you have your model you just compile
在這裡
right here
我是否印出了啟動碼只是為了展示給你
and did i print the activation just to show you
抱歉，我們回到上面去
sorry about this let's go back up
是的，你可以列印啟用
yeah you can print the activation
在那裡查看它是否真的使用了 soft max
right there to see if it is really using soft max
或 sigmoid
or sigmoid
我是說這是相當簡單的，它應該使用 softmax
i mean this is pretty straight forward it should be using soft max
因為這是多於一個的類別數
because this is a number of classes is more than one
好的
okay
所以這是讓我們往下看
so this is let's go down
一旦你定義了模型，接著你需要編譯它對吧
and once you have the model defined then you need to compile it right
因此，對於這個模型的編譯，你可以使用隨機梯度下降法
so for compilation of this model you can use a stochastic gradient descent
或者是基於隨機梯度下降法的一些東西
or something that's based on stochastic gradient descent type of
優化器
optimizer
所以在這個例子中，原子
so in this example atom
和損失函數
and loss function
在這個例子中，二元交叉熵
so in this example binary cross entropy
如果是多類別的話使用錯誤，對於多類別應該使用
which is the wrong one to use if it is multi-class for multi-class it should be
多類別交叉熵
multi-cross entropy
或者你知道分類交叉熵不是二元的
or you know categorical cross entropy not binary
好的，確保你使用正確的損失函數
okay make sure you use the right loss functions
然後是指標
and then for metrics
我現在會使用準確率，順便提一下我應該已經提過了
i'm going to use accuracy right now by the way i should already mention that
使用準確度作為語意分割的衡量指標是不好的
using an accuracy as a metric for semantic segmentation is not good
嗯，這不會給你結果，它會
well it's not going to give you it it is going to
你知道，它會收斂，不像
you know it's going to converge it's not like
但問題是達到 95%、98%、99% 的準確度很容易
but the problem is it's easy to get 95 98 99 accuracy
但結果仍然可能非常糟糕，那是因為準確度
but still get very horrible results that's because accuracy
包含背景
includes the background
如果背景很複雜而物體很少，那麼你可以達到 98%的準確度
if you have a lot of background very little of objects then you do get 98 accuracy
那麼在這種情況下，最佳的指標是什麼呢？
right so what is the best metric in that case
在這種情況下，最佳的指標會是某種被稱為
in that case the best metric would be something called
交集聯合指標 IOU
intersection over union iou
好的，這是最佳的指標
okay that's the best metric
我們會在接下來的教程中再次提到這個主題
and we will touch about that topic again in the upcoming tutorials
但現在讓我先停在這裡
but for now let me go ahead and stop here
因為
because
現在我們有一個運作良好的模型
now we have a model that works fine
我們有這個對於二元分類有效的模型
we have this model that works fine for binary
或多類別
or multi-class
那麼我們在下一個影片中開始吧
so let's start in the next video
我們來談談二元分類
let's talk about binary classification
讓我們看看如何將這應用到二元分類問題中
let's see how we can apply this to a binary classification problem
然後我們接下來來看看多類別分類
and the one after that let's look at multi-class classification
然後稍後我們會看看 3D 數據集
and then later on we'll look at 3d data sets
所以請繼續關注，訂閱這個頻道
and so on okay so please stay tuned subscribe to this channel
讓我們在下個影片見面
and let's meet in the next video